Welcome to our video best practices for creating brand names and logos.
Brand
names and logos can be powerful tools for sellers hoping to attract loyal
customers.
They help customers recognize and remember products and
distinguish one brand's goods from another's.
If you're a new brand in the
process of creating a brand name or logo, the most important thing to remember is
that it should represent your products.
Brand names and logos come in all shapes
and sizes.
There's no one way to create them but think carefully about the
products you sell and why customers might want to buy them before designing
your brand name or logo.
Ask what makes your products unique, valuable and
memorable.
You'll also want to keep these best practices in mind.
Stay simple.
The
best brand names are often short, easy to pronounce and straightforward to spell.
Make it memorable.
Your brand name and logo should stand out and be easy to
recognize and recall.
Stay descriptive.
Coming up with highly creative names is
fun but if they're too abstract or complicated they can prevent customers
from easily understanding your brand and products.
If you sell a particular
product you might want to include it in your name.
If your goods are of a certain
quality or type choose language or images that make that clear.
Create a brand name
or logo that helps customers attach meaning and value to your products.
For
example, if your products are eco-friendly consider associated words and images.
Finally, remember that if you're planning to sell your products in the
Amazon store using a logo it needs to include your brand name.
Logos and
brand names also need to be permanently affixed to your products or packaging.
These requirements help Amazon pair brands with the right products.
There's
also a couple of things to avoid while creating your brand name or logo.
You
don't want to use offensive or culturally inappropriate words or images.
Be sure
you also understand what the words and images in your brand name and logo mean
to a variety of audiences especially if you're translating text to another
language.
And avoid simply translating a brand name literally from one language
to another.
Brand names are culturally specific and translating them word for
word often means losing or changing the original meaning.
You also don't want to
create a name or logo that's too similar to a competitor's.
That won't help
distinguish your products from theirs and it could lead to claims of trademark
infringement or other legal or intellectual property issues.
Your brand
name and logo can use wordplay or newly invented words.
They can evoke a feeling
or emotion.
You can also stick to describing who you are and what you
produce.
However you choose to represent your products, take the time to brainstorm
and collect feedback on your brand name or logo.
It can be a good idea to consult
a brand agency or other expert too.
This concludes our best practices video.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store!